Richard A. Falk Papers
Richard A. Falk Papers
1954-1991
Falk, Richard A.
40 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, specialist in international law and justice. Collection includes extensive professional correspondence (1962-1991); manuscript and/or published articles, books, essays, lectures, speeches and other material on international law, war, the environment, nuclear weapons, the Middle-East, and population; and research material.
148969
Biographical History
Richard A. Falk (1930- ) is an American author and professor specializing in international law and justice. Born in New York City, he studied at University of Pennsylvania's Wharton School and graduated in 1952 with a B.S. in Economics. He attended Yale Law School, graduating in 1955 with an L.L.B., as well as Harvard Law School, earning his J.S.D. in 1962. Over his career he has been a faculty member at the College of Law, Ohio State University; the Albert G. Milbank Professor of International Law and Practice (now Professor Emeritus) at Princeton; Distinguished Visiting Professor of Law at Chapman University School of Law; and Visiting Distinguished Professor in Global and International Studies at the University of California, Santa Barbara (2001-2004). In addition to this distinction, Professor Falk has also been cited as a McCash Faculty and Ford Foundation Fellow.
Professor Falk is the author, co-author, or editor of more than thirty books and numerous essays, including The Six Legal Dimensions of the Vietnam War (1968), A Global Approach to National Policy (1975), Revolutionaries and Functionaries (1988), On Humane Governance: Toward a New Global Politics (1995), Crimes of War: Iraq (2006), and Achieving Human Rights (2008). He is a member of the editorial board of the American Journal of International Law, Foreign Policy, The Nation, and The Progressive, and editor of the Journal of Conflict Resolution. He is Chair of the Board of the Nuclear Age Peace Foundation and a member of the World Federalist Institute, the Independent International Commission on Kosovo, and the Advisory Board for the American Movement for World Government.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Richard A. Falk Papers consist of correspondence, personal material, printed material, published material, subject files, writings, and memorabilia. The collection at present consists of three separate accessions which have not been physically integrated; however, all material is listed in logical order below, so box numbers are not always sequential.
Correspondence contains a number of letters from well-known Congressmen and other public figures (a partial list of names of such people can be found in the finding aids file). The bulk of material found in printed material, published material and subject files deals with law and with the Vietnam War. Writings contains law-related works, many of which are in rough draft form. A selected index to correspondence listing notable figures (mainly members of Congress), appears at the end of the inventory; note that this index covers the main part of the collection ONLY (boxes 1-35). Correspondence from later additions (boxes 36-38) is not included in this index.
Personal material includes awards, correspondence, government employment information, photographs, and legal, medical, and financial papers.
Printed material includes business cards, newsletters, photocopies of articles, press releases, reports, transcripts, and other items.
Published material includes articles, clippings, galley proofs, magazines, pamphlets, photocopies, reprints, and other items.
Subject files consists of files on various topics related to Falk's areas of interest. Topics represented include -- but are by no means limited to -- aliens, arms control, the Carnegie Corporation, the Center for International Studies, coercion, disarmament, impeachment, indirect aggression, the Institute for World Order, international law, non-military foreign aid, nuclear proliferation, personal responsibility, reciprocity, South Africa, subversion, the United Nations, Vietnam, and war crimes.
Writings includes among other things articles, books, essays, galley proofs, lectures, and speeches. Also here are rough drafts and typescripts of dozens of pieces written by Falk.
Memorabilia contains conference material, printed material, publicity, and some miscellany.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is divided into general (organized chronologically) and specific (organized alphabetically by subject). Personal material, Subject files and Memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by topic, while Printed material is arranged alphabetically by type.
Published material and Writings present something of a challenge. These series are arranged inconsistently due to the three main sets of material not yet being physically integrated. Particularly problematic is the writings section, in which some items are categorized by type of material (essays, lectures, pamphlets), some are categorized by writing stage (proofs, typescripts, drafts), and still others are placed alphabetically by their topic. Researchers are encouraged to make a thorough reading of this section of the inventory.
Related Material
The library holds more than 60 volumes by Falk in its circulating collection; please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Falk, Richard A.; Princeton University. -- Center for International Studies.; Authors, American.; Detente.; Disarmament.; Ecology.; Educators -- United States.; Environmental law.; International organization.; International law.; International relations.; Nuclear warfare -- Moral and ethical aspects.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; War (International law); World politics.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Essays.; Lectures.; Manuscripts for publication.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Richard Falk, 1969-1992.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - [Chronological], 1962-1973; 26 folders (Box 1)
  - [Chronological], 1970-1972; 21 folders (Box 2)
  - [Chronological], 1972-1973; 18 folders (Box 3)
  - [Chronological], 1973-1975; 20 folders (Box 4)
  - [Chronological], 1975; 1977-1978,; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - [Chronological], 1984-1987 (Box 36)
  - [Chronological], 1991 (Box 37)
  - [Chronological], undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - A, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - American Foreign Law Association, Inc. (Box 5)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 5)
  - American Political Science Association Panel, 1973 (Box 5)
  - ASIL (American Society of International Law)
    - Covert Intervention (Box 5)
    - Executive Committee (Box 5)
    - War-Peace Arena (Box 5)
  - Amnesty International Conference, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Arab-Israeli (Box 5)
  - Arms Control Disarmament Agency Study (Box 5)
  - Atlantic Council (Box 5)
  - B, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Batra, Tarlok Singh (Box 5)
  - Bishop, William J., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Board of Review and Development, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - C, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Cambridge, International, etc. (Box 6)
  - Catholic Association for International Peace Conference, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Studies (Box 6)
  - Center of International Studies (Box 6)
  - Clergy and Laymen Concerned About Vietnam, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Columbia Society of International Law (Box 6)
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace (Box 6)
  - Commitments (Box 6)
  - Conference on Future of International Law (Box 6)
  - Conference Sites for Peace Talks (Box 6)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Crown, Joseph (Box 6)
  - D, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Dayal, Rajeshwar (Box 6)
  - E, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - F, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Fisheries Conference (Box 6)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 6)
  - Bruce Franklin (Box 6)
  - Fund for Peace (Box 6)
  - G, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - H, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Haiphong Letter (Box 6)
  - Hammarskjold Forums, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Hanoi and Paris, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Human Rights Committee (Box 6)
  - I (Box 7)
  - Incoming, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Institute for Global Concerns (Box 7)
  - Institute for World Order (Box 7)
  - International Affairs Seminars (Box 7)
  - International Law Association (Box 7)
  - International Law Society (Box 7)
  - International League for the Rights of Man (Box 7)
  - International Procedures to Protect Private Rights Research Project (Box 7)
  - International Society, 1968 (Box 7)
  - J (Box 7)
  - Japan (Box 7)
  - Journal of Conflict Resolution (Box 7)
  - K, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Kunz Volume (Box 7)
  - L, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Lawyers' Committee on American Policy Toward Vietnam (Box 7)
  - Legal Advisor's Office (Box 7)
  - Legal Order in a Violent World (Box 7)
  - Letter from a Soldier in Vietnam (Box 7)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company (Box 7)
  - London Times article (Box 7)
  - M, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Mc (Box 7)
  - McCosh Fellowship (Box 7)
  - Mendlovitz-Falk (Box 7)
  - The Middle East in the Contemporary World, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous personal correspondence, 1962 (Box 7)
  - N, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ (Box 7)
  - Neutralization (Box 7)
  - Neutralization Revision (Box 7)
  - New York Bar Association Committee of International Law (Box 8)
  - New York Times (Box 8)
  - New York University Conference on Norms (Box 8)
  - Nobel Peace Prize (Box 8)
  - Nuremberg Threshing Group (Box 8)
  - O, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Observer's Report-South Africa (Box 8)
  - Outgoing correspondence (Box 8)
  - P, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Pandora's Halo, poems (Box 8)
  - Princeton Press (Box 8)
  - Princeton University Conference (Box 8)
  - Procedural Aspects International Law Institute (Box 8)
  - Politics 317 (Box 8)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory (Box 8)
  - Q (Box 8)
  - R, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Reader in International Law and International Organization (Box 8)
  - Recommendations, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - References, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Rhodesia (Box 8)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 8)
  - S, 6 folders (Box 8)
  - Seminar on Law and World Order, 1968 (Box 8)
  - South Africa, Bishop Mize (Box 8)
  - South West Africa (Box 8)
  - Harold Sprout (Box 9)
  - The Status of Law in International Society (Box 9)
  - Julius Stone (Box 9)
  - Stress (Box 9)
  - Student Forum on International Order and World Peace (Box 9)
  - Student Recommendations (Box 9)
  - Syracuse book (Box 9)
  - T, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Tax Protest (Box 9)
  - Theory (Box 9)
  - Tshombe Case (Box 9)
  - U (Box 9)
  - U.S. Sponsoring and Policy Review Council (Box 9)
  - University Conference on Disarmament (Box 9)
  - V (Box 9)
  - Vanderbilt University Lecture, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Vietnam, letters (Box 9)
  - Vietnam, Lawyer's Committee (Box 9)
  - W, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - World Bank (Box 9)
  - World Conference of Lawyers for Vietnam, 1968 (Box 9)
  - World Law Fund, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - World Law Fund Conference, 1968 (Box 9)
  - World Order Models Project [WOMP] (Box 9)
  - World Order Studies Project (Box 9)
  - Quincy Wright Festschrift (Box 9)
  - X-Y-Z (Box 9)
- Personal
  - Awards (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1975 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1961-1971 (Box 9)
  - Financial, 1962-1974 (Box 9)
  - Government employment information, 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Legal and medical, 1962-1969 (Box 9)
  - Personal files (Box 37)
  - Photographs (Box 9)
- Printed material
  - Application for Review of Judgement No. 158 of the United Nations Administrative Tribunal (Box 9)
  - Articles, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Articles (Box 10)
  - Business cards (Box 10)
  - Co-Existence and Common Existence (Box 10)
  - Education for a Planet in Peril (Box 10)
  - Invitations (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 15 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Newsletters, 1962-1975; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Photocopies
    - International Law and the Deprivation of Foreign Wealth (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 9 folders (Box 12)
    - Ocean Sciences, Technology, and the Future International Law of the Sea (Box 12)
    - The Relevance of International Law to Emerging Trends in the Law of Outer Space (Box 12)
    - The Relevance of International Law to the Processes of Economic and Social Development (Box 12)
    - The South West Africa Cases, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Transcripts, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Transcripts, 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Press Releases (Box 13)
  - Printed stationery (Box 13)
  - The Procedural Aspects of International Law Institute Reports, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Reports, 1966-1973; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Toward Minimizing the Use of Nuclear Weapons (Box 13)
  - Transcripts, 1970 (Box 13)
  - Work, Wages, and Apartheid (Box 13)
  - World Order Models Project State of the Globe Message, 1975; 2 folders (Box 13)
- Published material
  - Articles, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Bloc activities (Box 13)
  - Wm. [William F. ] Buckley (Box 13)
  - Clippings
    - London Times (Box 13)
    - Magazine, 1968-1975 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Pentagon Study (Box 13)
  - Cuba-Latin America (Box 13)
  - Death on the High Seas (Box 13)
  - Galleys
    - International Law (Box 13)
    - Sex, Love, and Human Relationships (Box 13)
  - Magazines
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-1973 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967-1975 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969-1973 (Box 14)
    - The Nation, 1964-1966 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous publications
    - 1963-1971 (Box 14)
    - 1964-1974 (Box 14)
    - 1966-1972 (Box 14)
    - 1967-1970 (Box 14)
    - 1967-1972 (Box 14)
  - Monroe Doctrine (Box 14)
  - National Interest-World Order (Box 14)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1962-1975 (Box 14)
    - 1962-1971 (Box 14)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 14)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 14)
  - Newspapers, 1974 (Oversize 1)
  - Pamphlets (Box 14)
  - Peace (Box 14)
  - Peace in Vietnam (Box 14)
  - Photocopies
    - After Songmy (Box 14)
    - Aquarius, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Army Field Manual Provisions (Box 14)
    - Articles (Box 14)
    - Brussels Convention (Box 15)
    - Dyson (Box 15)
    - Eichmann Prosecution (Box 15)
    - FDR (Box 15)
    - Jackson Opening Statement (Box 15)
    - Korematsu, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Lewy (Box 15)
    - London Charter (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Moscow Declaration (Box 15)
    - Nurnberg Judgement (Box 15)
    - Reel (Box 15)
    - Reviews of RAF (Box 15)
    - Tokyo Judgement (Box 15)
  - Problems of Infranational Character (Box 15)
  - Recognition
    - Admission (Box 15)
    - Diplomatic Protests (Box 15)
  - Regionalism Functions (Box 15)
  - Reprints, 1957-1971 (Box 15)
  - Social problems (Box 15)
  - Treaty arrangements (Box 15)
  - Vietnam
    - The Constitutional issue (Box 15)
    - Internal politics (Box 15)
    - Internal War, Laos (Box 15)
    - Other Conflict Reactions (Box 15)
    - War Crimes (Box 15)
    - Vietnam as Civil War (Box 15)
- Subject files
  - Academic material (Box 36)
  - Act-State (Box 15)
  - AFSC, war crimes (Box 15)
  - Aliens (Box 15)
  - American Journal of International Law, book reviews (Box 15)
  - ASIL
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Policy Positions (Box 15)
    - Committee on Governance (Box 15)
    - Covert Intervention (Box 15)
    - General, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Panel II: Government Decision-Making (Box 15)
    - Proposal: International Environmental Programs (Box 15)
  - Analogies to International Relations (Box 15)
  - Anshen Institute (Box 15)
  - The Apollo Complex (Box 15)
  - Arms Control at Princeton (Box 15)
  - Arms Control, Disarmament, and World Order (Box 15)
  - Artists Seminar (Box 15)
  - Berlin, Germany (Box 15)
  - Berrigan, general information (Box 15)
  - Biological and chemical warfare (Box 15)
  - Boehm Study (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Discussion on the General Assembly (Box 15)
  - CIS (Center for International Studies)
    - Acting Director R.A. Falk (Box 15)
    - Ad Committee (Box 15)
    - Affiliation (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Subcommittee (Box 15)
  - Citizen's Commission (Box 15)
  - Civil Defense (Box 15)
  - Civil War
    - A-Z, 5 folders (Box 15)
    - Memos (Box 15)
    - Panel, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Studies: Guidelines (Box 15)
    - Studies: Names and Titles (Box 15)
    - Study Group Addresses (Box 15)
  - Coercion (Box 15)
  - Columbia Course, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Commission on the Organization of the Government (Box 16)
  - Committee of Liaison (Box 16)
  - Computer course (Box 16)
  - Conference of Laws (Box 16)
  - Consultative Council (Box 16)
  - CONTACT (Box 16)
  - Convocation, World Environment (Box 16)
  - Courses
    - [General], 1966 (Box 16)
    - Middle East (Box 16)
    - P.A. 545, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Pol. 317, 5 folders (Box 16)
    - Politics 545, 1967 (Box 16)
    - Politics Generals (Box 16)
    - Politics of Disarmament (Box 16)
    - Public Affairs 559, 1973 (Box 16)
    - World Order (Box 16)
  - Creative Arts and World Order (Box 16)
  - The Dependence of Peace Upon Disarmament (Box 16)
  - Diplomatic Immunities (Box 16)
  - Disarmament, general (Box 16)
  - Disarmament without inspection (Box 16)
  - Domestic Implication of the Cold War for Administration of Law (Box 16)
  - The Ecology Culture (Box 16)
  - EP Comments (Box 16)
  - Faculty Committee on Ph.D. Programs (Box 16)
  - Faculty Council on Vietnam (Box 16)
  - Foreign Policy Consensus (Box 16)
  - Fund for Peace, Trustees Meeting (Box 16)
  - Future of WOMP [World Order Models Project], 1973 (Box 16)
  - Future Society (Box 16)
  - General Assembly Resolutions (Box 16)
  - General and Complete Disarmament (Box 16)
  - Global Goals, Thomas Jones (Box 16)
  - Grand Jury (Box 16)
  - Greece, Civil War (Box 16)
  - Greece, Lebanon, etc. (Box 16)
  - Herman, Chomsky (Box 16)
  - Human rights, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Ideology (Box 17)
  - Impeachment (Box 17)
  - Indirect aggression (Box 17)
  - Individual (Box 17)
  - The Individual and the Government (Box 17)
  - Individual SWO (Box 17)
  - Institute for Global Concerns, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Institute for World Order
    - Executive Committee (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - International Adjudication (Box 17)
  - International Aspects of Federalism (Box 17)
  - International Law and US Military Practices (Box 17)
  - International Law and War (Box 17)
  - International Law Committee (Box 17)
  - International Law of International Travel (Box 17)
  - International Relations (Box 17)
  - Kennedy (Box 17)
  - Kissinger confirmation (Box 17)
  - Law and Foreign Policy (Box 17)
  - Law and Public Affairs (Box 17)
  - Law, war, morality, etc. (Box 17)
  - Legislative intervention by United Nations (Box 17)
  - Mathmatica (Box 17)
  - McDougal (Box 17)
  - Military Assistance (Box 17)
  - Morse, Ed (Box 17)
  - National Parks and Conservation Association, 1975; 1976; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - New States (Box 17)
  - Nigeria (Box 17)
  - Non-Aligned Nations (Box 17)
  - Non-Member Issue (Box 17)
  - Non-Military Foreign Aid (Box 17)
  - Nuclear Proliferation (Box 17)
  - Nuclear Testing (Box 17)
  - Nuclear Warfare and Moral Responsibility (Box 17)
  - Obstacles to Disarmament (Box 17)
  - Ohio State University (Box 17)
  - Outer Space and International Law (Box 17)
  - Peace Research and Education (Box 17)
  - Peace, System Change (Box 17)
  - Pentagon Papers Case (Box 17)
  - Personal Responsibility and War (Box 17)
  - Politics Department (Box 18)
  - Politics of Law in International Society (Box 18)
  - Population Control (Box 18)
  - Population Effects (Box 18)
  - Princeton University
    - Burlingham (Box 18)
    - Course and Faculty Information, 1964-1968; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Courses, etc. (Box 18)
    - Conference on World Order (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - World Order Studies Program (Box 18)
  - Possible Candidates for World Order Program (Box 18)
  - Procedural Aspects of International Law Institute (Box 18)
  - Proliferation (Box 18)
  - Quotations (Box 18)
  - Rand-McNally and Company (Box 18)
  - Reciprocity (Box 18)
  - Recommendations, 1963-1965; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Redress (Box 18)
  - Redress Conference, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Regionalism, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Regional Meetings (Box 18)
  - Rosenau (Box 18)
  - Select Vietnam Reading List (Box 18)
  - Self-Determination (Box 18)
  - Shimoda Book (Box 18)
  - Sixth Committee ILC (Box 18)
  - Social Problems (Box 18)
  - South Africa (Box 18)
  - State As Obsolete Statement (Box 18)
  - State of the Globe Message (Box 18)
  - State of the Globe Overview (Box 18)
  - Steel Seizure
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Youngstown Sheet and Tube, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Subversion (Box 18)
  - Tape of Panel Discussion, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Theory (Box 18)
  - Thon, War Crimes Book (Box 18)
  - Threats (Box 18)
  - Trade, WOMP [World Order Models Project] (Box 18)
  - Unilateral Claiming Processes (Box 18)
  - UNITAR Project (Box 18)
  - United Nations
    - Financing (Box 19)
    - Intervention (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Report on Appreciation of International Law (Box 19)
    - Versus Fasla (Box 19)
    - World Population Conference, 1974 (Box 19)
  - United States Disarmament Agency (Box 19)
  - University Regulations (Box 19)
  - Vietnam
    - And International Law (Box 19)
    - Bowen vs. US, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Duffy Interrogation (Box 19)
    - Elections (Box 19)
    - Frances Fitzgerald (Box 19)
    - Ashley King Letter (Box 19)
    - Lawyers' Committee (Box 19)
    - Levy vs. US Army, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Mitchell vs. US (Box 19)
    - Mora vs. McNamara (Box 19)
    - Moratorium (Box 19)
    - Nixon on My Lai, 1969 (Box 19)
    - Noyd, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Owens, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Roger Priest Case (Box 19)
    - Princeton Alumni Panel (Box 19)
    - Princeton University General Assembly (Box 19)
    - Protest: The Moral Issues (Box 19)
    - Reitemeyer vs. McCrea (Box 19)
    - Scripts and Time Sheets (Box 19)
    - Sisson vs. US (Box 19)
    - Statement by Canadian Lawyers (Box 19)
    - Torture (Box 19)
    - US vs. Mitchell (Box 19)
    - Tran Van Dinh (Box 19)
    - Vermont (Box 19)
    - Welsh vs. US (Box 19)
  - War Crimes (Box 19)
  - War Crimes Reader (Box 19)
  - War and National Responsibility, 1970 (Box 19)
  - War Prevention (Box 19)
  - Warsaw Convention (Box 19)
  - War System (Box 19)
  - Woodrow Wilson School
    - Curriculum Committee (Box 20)
    - General (Box 20)
  - World Law Fund
    - Editorial Committee (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - World Order Conference Papers (Box 20)
  - WOMP [World Order Models Project]
    - [General], 1970 (Box 20)
    - Northfield Conference, 1973 (Box 20)
    - Specific notes (Box 20)
  - WOMP II [World Order Models Project] (Box 20)
  - World Order Studies (Box 20)
  - Yale Lecture, 1962 (Box 20)
- Writings
  - Anarchism and World Order (Box 20)
  - Articles
    - Circle of Responsibility (Box 20)
    - The Revolution in Peace Education (Box 20)
    - United States Versus Russo (Box 20)
  - A World Order Perspective on Authoritarian Tendencies (Box 20)
  - Book jacket, A Global Approach to National Policy (Box 20)
  - Book jacket, This Endangered Planet (Box 20)
  - Books
    - Book information (oversize) (Oversize 2)
    - Explorations at the Edge of Time, manuscript draft (Box 36)
    - The Role of Domestic Courts in the Development of International Legal Order, setting copy for front matter and 7 chapters; 8 folders (Box 39)
    - Viet II Permissions (Box 20)
  - Cambodia and International Law (Box 20)
  - Civil War (Box 20)
  - Consensus (Box 20)